<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on &gt; h4ckery.b1nx</title>
    <link>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on &gt; h4ckery.b1nx</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 23:06:10 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zbinx.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using filebrowser in portainer to access fileserver</title>
      <link>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/filebrowser-portainer-fileserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 23:06:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/filebrowser-portainer-fileserver/</guid>
      <description>I run a Samba server on my home server to backup files, host pictures, movies, and more. Recently, I discovered a new feature called &amp;ldquo;filebrowser&amp;rdquo; that adds a web interface to access files on my server in a web browser of my choice. With filebrowser, I can simply browse to the URL of the filebrowser address, log in with my username, and then have access to whatever files the admin allows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valheim seed reader coded in BASH</title>
      <link>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/valheim-seed-reader-bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 23:15:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/valheim-seed-reader-bash/</guid>
      <description>How to find the Seed number for your Valheim World in Linux. If you&amp;rsquo;re a fan of Valheim, you know that finding the right seed number is crucial to creating the perfect world. The problem is, it&amp;rsquo;s not always easy or convenient to find that number. That&amp;rsquo;s where my latest project comes in.
I&amp;rsquo;ve created a simple script that you can run on your Linux server to quickly find the seed number for your Valheim world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating &amp; Using Public Key Authentication</title>
      <link>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/sshkeys/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 23:24:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/sshkeys/</guid>
      <description>You can configure your Linux server to use public key authentication instead of a password by following these steps:   Generate a public and private key pair on your local machine:
 You can use the ssh-keygen command to generate a new key pair. This will create two files in the ~/.ssh directory: a private key (id_rsa) and a public key (id_rsa.pub).    Copy the public key to the server:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Cyber 2022: Day 04 - Scanning</title>
      <link>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/aoc22_scanning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 16:06:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/aoc22_scanning/</guid>
      <description>Learning objectives  What is Scanning? Scanning types Scanning techniques Scanning tools  What is Scanning? Scanning is a set of procedures for identifying live hosts, ports and services, discovering the OS of target system &amp;amp; identifying vulnerabilities &amp;amp; threats in the network. Scanning reveals parts of the attack surface for attackers and allows launching targeted attacks to exploit the system.
Scanning Types Scanning is classified as either active or passive based on the intrusiveness to gathering info about a target system or network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding with Golang course on YouTube</title>
      <link>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/golangintro-1-30-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 20:45:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/golangintro-1-30-23/</guid>
      <description>Youtube: Golang Tutorial for beginners My coding skills have been RUSTY! I think its time to brush up on my Golang. This time it will be with this free Golang tutorial for beginners offered from the great FreeCodeCamp.org folks. I will be doing this whole course over the next couple weeks and will report back with my findings.
Ultimately I would like to be proficient at a couple languages. I want to create some linux &amp;amp; infosec tools but I would also like to expand my coding skillset to make me a stronger security researcher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating docker containers with Portainer on linux</title>
      <link>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/updatedockerportainer1-15-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 22:53:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/updatedockerportainer1-15-23/</guid>
      <description>How to update docker containers &amp;amp; portainer on your homelab. I got into the whole Portainer craze when I found out about containers and their uses. This really cool tech lets you manage your servers utilizing containers. In short&amp;hellip;.containers are lightweight, standalone applications that let you quickly build, test and deploy applications. It also helps you manage complex server setups when you want to run different software without worrying about them conflicting with each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feb 14th blog</title>
      <link>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/feb_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 21:42:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/feb_14/</guid>
      <description>Testing this blog post to ensure functionality of website testing testing testing blah blah blah blah</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February Update</title>
      <link>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/februaryblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 23:08:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/februaryblog/</guid>
      <description>Been a little while since I posted on this website. Been a busy couple months but I still managed to keep my TryHackMe streak running strong, 1 day away from 100 days of hacking!
Updates:
  Set up a Rasberry-pi 4 NAS server running OpenMediaVault hosting a file server ( samba ).
  Set up a dedicated Valheim server using an amazing linux script fully coded in Bash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo cheatsheet and commands</title>
      <link>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/hugo-cheatsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 01:05:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/hugo-cheatsheet/</guid>
      <description> Basic commands   Create new post: hugo new posts/nameofpost.md
  Create new post in different directory: hugo new writeups/2019/nameofpost.md
  Testing website with live updates: hugo server -D
  Images  Store your images in the content/images directory  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualbox Guest Additions install / guide</title>
      <link>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/vboxguestadds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 11:31:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/vboxguestadds/</guid>
      <description>What is VirtualBox guest additions? Guest Additions is simply just an add-on for your VirtualBox application so you can fully utilize vbox to its full potential. Some people think that once you install virtualbox and the OS of your choice, that you are then good to go. If you do not install guest additions on top of your new OS vbox, then you might not have full resolution, dual monitor support, full screen, copy / paste etc&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TryHackMe room: Attacktive Directory - writeup</title>
      <link>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/thmroom_ad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 17:48:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/thmroom_ad/</guid>
      <description>TryHackMe room: Attacktive Directory  99% of Corporate networks run off of AD. But can you exploit a vulnerable Domain Controller?
 Task 1: Enumeration   create temporary alias for IP address, rather than typing it out every time.
export ip=10.10.89.177
  run nmap of target:
nmap -sC -sV -oN nmap/initial.txt $ip
   1. What tool will allow us to enumerate port 139/445? Answer: enum4linux 2. What is the NetBIOS-Domain Name of the machine?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THM room: Active Directory Basics</title>
      <link>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/adbasics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 23:06:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/adbasics/</guid>
      <description>Active Directory Basics  What is Active directory? Active Directory is a collection of machines and servers connected inside of domains, that are a collective part of a bigger forest of domains, that make up the Active Directory network. Active Directory contains many functioning bits and pieces, a majority of which we will be covering in the upcoming tasks. To outline what we&amp;rsquo;ll be covering take a look over this list of Active Directory components and become familiar with the various pieces of Active Directory:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TryHackMe walkthrough for room: Nessus</title>
      <link>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/nessus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 16:14:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/nessus/</guid>
      <description>TryHackMe room: Nessus &amp;ldquo;Learn how to set up and use Nessus, a popular vulnerability scanner.&amp;rdquo; Nessus vulnerability scanner is exactly what you think is its! A vulnerability scanner! It uses techniques similar to Nmap to find and report vulnerabilities, which are then, presented in a nice GUI for us to look at. Nessus is different from other scanners as it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make assumptions when scanning, like assuming the web application is running on port 80 for instance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix: code block unreadable due to config</title>
      <link>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/highlightfix/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 15:34:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/highlightfix/</guid>
      <description>How to fix the unreadable code block that happens in certain themes / configs:  With certain themes you may encounter an issue where you will have unreadable code block highlighting.
 Add the following code at the end of your config.toml  [markup] [markup.highlight] anchorLineNos = false codeFences = true guessSyntax = false hl_Lines = &amp;#39;&amp;#39; lineAnchors = &amp;#39;&amp;#39; lineNoStart = 1 lineNos = false lineNumbersInTable = true noClasses = true style = &amp;#39;vim&amp;#39; tabWidth = 4 pygmentsStyle = &amp;#34;vim&amp;#34;  Edit the following 2 lines:  style = &amp;#39;vim&amp;#39; pygmentsStyle = &amp;#34;vim&amp;#34; You can change these to other chroma styles but the vim one worked best for my current config.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to properly deploy public hugo website</title>
      <link>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/hugodeploy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 09:13:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/hugodeploy/</guid>
      <description>Deploying Hugo public site via github hosting  define Hugo: Hugo is a fast and modern static site generator written in Go, and designed to make website creation fun again.
 At this point you should have 2 repos for your hugo website uploaded to github.
 source code repo public deployment repo  make directories for both repos locally.
mkdir sourceCodeHugoSite mkdir publicDeploymentHugoSite Then clone them into their respective directories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to fix git issue with deploying hugo public site</title>
      <link>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/how_fix_git_issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 21:25:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/how_fix_git_issue/</guid>
      <description>I kept breaking my site deployment because of an issue with handling the multiple repos and folders from multiple computers. To summarize: When making a hugo deployment site, you should have 2 separate folders. 1 for the source code and the other for public deployment.
 Clone both repos to their own folders locally. git pull inside both so you are up to date with the remote repo. Once changes are made in source code, push the changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git command to save credentials when push/pull</title>
      <link>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/github_login9-14-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 15:21:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/github_login9-14-21/</guid>
      <description>How to update git to save your credentials when pulling / pushing? Run the following command:
git config --global credential.helper store Attention: This method saves the credentials in plaintext on your PC&amp;rsquo;s disk. Everyone on your computer can access it, e.g. malicious NPM modules. The credentials are stored in a file on the disk, with the disk permissions of &amp;ldquo;just user readable/writable&amp;rdquo; but still in plaintext.
If the password is changed at some point, your git pull / push will fail and git will then remove the offending user+password from the ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown syntax example post</title>
      <link>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/blog1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:54:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/blog1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article offers a sample of basic Markdown syntax that can be used in Hugo content files, also it shows whether basic HTML elements are decorated with CSS in a Hugo theme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>