<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tryhackme on &gt; h4ckery.b1nx</title>
    <link>https://zbinx.github.io/tags/tryhackme/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tryhackme on &gt; h4ckery.b1nx</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 16:06:09 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zbinx.github.io/tags/tryhackme/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Cyber 2022: Day 04 - Scanning</title>
      <link>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/aoc22_scanning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 16:06:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/aoc22_scanning/</guid>
      <description>Learning objectives  What is Scanning? Scanning types Scanning techniques Scanning tools  What is Scanning? Scanning is a set of procedures for identifying live hosts, ports and services, discovering the OS of target system &amp;amp; identifying vulnerabilities &amp;amp; threats in the network. Scanning reveals parts of the attack surface for attackers and allows launching targeted attacks to exploit the system.
Scanning Types Scanning is classified as either active or passive based on the intrusiveness to gathering info about a target system or network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THM room: Active Directory Basics</title>
      <link>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/adbasics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 23:06:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/adbasics/</guid>
      <description>Active Directory Basics  What is Active directory? Active Directory is a collection of machines and servers connected inside of domains, that are a collective part of a bigger forest of domains, that make up the Active Directory network. Active Directory contains many functioning bits and pieces, a majority of which we will be covering in the upcoming tasks. To outline what we&amp;rsquo;ll be covering take a look over this list of Active Directory components and become familiar with the various pieces of Active Directory:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TryHackMe walkthrough for room: Nessus</title>
      <link>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/nessus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 16:14:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zbinx.github.io/posts/nessus/</guid>
      <description>TryHackMe room: Nessus &amp;ldquo;Learn how to set up and use Nessus, a popular vulnerability scanner.&amp;rdquo; Nessus vulnerability scanner is exactly what you think is its! A vulnerability scanner! It uses techniques similar to Nmap to find and report vulnerabilities, which are then, presented in a nice GUI for us to look at. Nessus is different from other scanners as it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make assumptions when scanning, like assuming the web application is running on port 80 for instance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>